IORTSOR BRIGHT IWANGER

Frontend Engineer

Frontend Developer with over 1 year of experience developing and maintaining user friendly web applications. Proficient in frontend technologies such as React, Vue, Javascript, CSS, Tailwindcss, MUI, git & GitHub with a strong understanding of responsive design and performance optimization. Excellent communication and problem solving skills developed over years of related work experience.

Work History

08/2022-Current

Frontend Developer

Kinatech Innovative, Abuja, FCT

- Developing responsive web applications with modern Javascript frameworks like React and Vue.
- Monitor and report on key metrics such as page load time, time to interact and conversion rates to identify areas of improvement.
- Implementing search engine optimization and improving business reach by 50%.
- Learning and adopting new techniques to improve web security and overall user interface and frontend architecture.

04/2022 -Current

Frontend Engineer

AltSchool Africa, Remote.

- Lead the development and implementation of responsive web application to ensure compatibility across all screens using React.js and Vue.js frameworks.
- Collaborate with designers and backend engineers to define, design and ship new features thus creating a seamless user experience and improving conversion rates by at least 30%.
- Write unit and integration tests to ensure quality and reliability of code.

Contact

Address

Abuja, Nigeria

Phone

+2347038501811

E-mail

iortsor@gmail.com

Portfolio

https://brightiortsor.netlify.ap

LinkedIn

https://www.linkedin.com/in/brightiortsor

Skills

Networking



Creativity



Analytical and Critical Thinking



Interpersonal
Communication



01/2022 -05/2022

Frontend Engineer

Side Hustle, Remote

- Developed and maintained the user interface of web applications.
- Integrated enhancements into web design to improve user stickiness, smooth functionality and boost load times.
- Worked closely with designers and backend engineers to ensure seamless user experience.
- Continuously improved the performance, usability and accessibility of web applications.

07/2021 - 08/2022

Customer Service Executive

NISA Premier, Abuja, Nigeria

- Provided company information and policies to customers upon inquiry and answered questions via phone, email or online chat.
- Escalated critical customer issues to supervisor to avoid lost revenue and canceled policies.
- Made reasonable procedure exceptions to accommodate unusual customer requests.
- Provided primary customer support to internal and external customers.
- Clarified customer issues and determined root cause of problems to resolve product or service complaints.

Education

2013-03 -

Bachelor of Technology: Microbiology

2018-10

Federal University of Technology - Minna, Nigeria

Second Class Upper

2009-09 -2012-07

Senior School Certificate

Government Secondary School - Gwagwalada, Abuja

Software

Javascript(ES6)

React.is

Vue.js

CSS

Tailwindcss

Bootstrap

SCSS/SASS

Ant Design

Material UI

HTML5

Git

GitHub